

Technologist & Designer

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a designer and technologist, I am obsessed with understanding the mechanism by which technology delivers us into an alternative future. As a design researcher, I learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of ethnographic research techniques that help to resist the internal inertia that new technologies tend to assert and to instead apply user-centered, systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

SKIIS

Design Research UI/UX Design R, SPSS, Python, Torch Software Engineering Hardware Engineering Public Speaking Project Management Product Design

work experience

SEIU International

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA Senior Data Product Manager Led design and development of in-house financial-member system handling 25M records, 50 corp. partners, \$5M revenue.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU Design Researcher / Lecturer Researched community fablabs at the Center for Media, Data and Society at CEU in Budapest. Also piloted OpenLab public design workshops teaching UXR, interface design and hardware/software prototyping for public projects.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

Research Manager Managed a democratic capacity mapping project for the MIT Community Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor as well as designed and engineered a democratic capacity mapping and organizational partnership tool.

Civic Tech Fellow

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA UXR / Designer / Engineer Developed civic technology for the City of Cambridge, focussing on easy to deploy open source citizen analytics apps and consulting with GoINVO on the MA SNAP application redesign.

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

OutVote.io & Commit.vote - Founder / Director of Product Founded civic tech startup COMM!T to test efficacy of peer-enforced smart contracts in driving civic participation. Joined forces w/ OutVote civic networking app post-election 2017.